Hissah Alotaibi

hissahalotaibi5@gmail.com +966538121110

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hissah-khalid-985057199/

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am a fresh graduate with a master's degree in computer science from the University of Melbourne. My primary area of expertise is in business analysis. My master's research at Melbourne university focused on discovering clients' requirements for financial systems to improve the work of these systems. I am keen to improve my skills and accelerate my knowledge by collaborating with you.

EDUCATION

Jul 2019 - Jul 2022 Master of Computer Science

The University of Melbourne, Australia

Grade: 3.69/4

May 2013 - May 2018 Bachelor of Computer Science

Jazan University, Saudi Arabia

• Grade: 4.69/5

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

March 2018 - June 2018 Software Engineer Intern

Jazan University, Saudi Arabia

- Demonstrate and recognise basic key concepts in computer operations and service facilities.
- Determine leadership and employability skills through effective written and oral communication.
- Solved various programming issues along with handling certain product devices
- Establish competency in the installation of software on different operating systems.

Jun 2021 - June 2022

Software Developer, Tutor

Victorian Certificate of Education, Australia

• Teaching high school programming requirements that students are to use when developing working modules and purpose-designed solutions.

We focus on the development of the working modules and software solutions; the chosen programming language should provide students with the ability to carry out the development stage of the problem-solving methodology within three conceptual layers: interface, logic and data source.

Sep2022-Oct 2022

Data analytics Consultant, Contract

LOGGO IP PTY LTD ,Australia

 Apply theoretical knowledge and develop problem-solving skills through providing valuable insights to a business client.
 Writing the project plans and reports.

We are doing a Presentation to the client. Working through Practera (a progressive web app)

Skills: Service Oriented · Problem Solver · Innovator · Collaborative Work · Team Leadership

PROJECTS

Jul 2020 - Nov 2020 Al Autonomy and Planning

University of Melbourne, Australia

- Coding by Python language AI-based Pacman autonomous agents to compete in a tournament. utilizing different AI technique to complete projects such as Monte Carlo, Heuristic function and A-Star methods
- Engaging work and managed alongside a team, meeting timetable, and achieving high score
 H1

Jul 2019 - Mar 2022 Machine learning

University of Melbourne, Australia

- Trained a logistic regression model to predict whether borrowers would default on their loans based on the Lending Club data. Also, trained a logistic regression model to predict whether an employee is likely to resign using an employee turnover dataset. The model achieved an accuracy of 85% on Lending Club data and on the employee's turnover dataset the model achieved an accuracy of 80%.
- Explored geolocation of Tweets with Machine Learning algorithm

Jul 2021 - Jul 2022 Actionable AI decision-making

University of Melbourne, Australia

• To solve the problem of actionability of decisions making, I used the Structured Interview and Task Reflection methods to elicit information about actionable factors from users' mental models that can be used to improve AI systems (loan and employee turnover systems). These methods provided a guick peek at mental models and rich information about participants.

Mar 2020 - May 2020 Usability Testing and User Experience (UX)

University of Melbourne, Australia

- Evaluating usability and user experience for different websites and applications by deploying different methods, such as Cognitive walkthrough and Heuristic evaluation for No user involvement
- Implement interviews, questionnaires and observations for testing usability and knowing User Experience for designing a website.
- Implement usability Test on Vans website as a teamwork with received positive feedback from supervises with grade 88/100

Jul 2020 - Nov 2020 Old Quad Gallery Website design - Fieldwork for Design

University of Melbourne, Australia

- Analysed interviews with visitor experiences and developed persona
- Design a website based on a persona from visitor experiences
- Engaging work and managed alongside a team. Received H1 score with good feedback on analysis and design from the manager.

July 2019 - Jun 2022 Da

Data Analysis

University of Melbourne, Australia

- I work with two datasets: Lending Club and IBM HR Analytics Employee Attrition Performance
- Tidy data using the tidyverse to facilitate analysis better Wrangle data using dplyr
- Using descriptive analysis and inference analysis to analyse data

RESEARCH

Jul 2020 - Nov 2020 Socia

Social Science and Explainable AI in Medicine: A Literature

University of Melbourne, Australia

- This paper reviews the literature on Explainable AI for the medical system that investigates the theoretic of human decision-making and representation from the fields of social science.
- I got an Excellent grade with good feedback from my supervisor.

Mar 2021 - Jul 2022

Actionability of AI decision making

University of Melbourne, Australia

 An experimental study with a mixed approach to solving problem of actionability of Al comprehensively, summited at AAAI conference

ADDITIONAL COURSEWORK

Statistics training course

Australia

- Core Statistics Concepts Descriptive statistics, distributions, hypothesis testing, and regression
 - Bayesian Thinking Conditional probability, prior, posteriors, and maximum likelihood
- Intro to Statistical Machine Learning
- Learning basic machine concepts and how statistics fit in the Programming course (in python)

Python

Australia

- Learning to use lists, tuples, loops, decision statements, etc.
- · Working with Exception handling, Inheritance
- work independently in projects with scripting and Automation
- Master Python 3 by making10 amazing Python apps

Data Science: Wrangling

Udemy

- How to import data into R from different file formats
- How to scrape data from the web
- How to tidy data using the tidyverse to better facilitate analysis
- How to process strings with regular expressions (regex)
- How to wrangle data using dplyr
- How to work with dates and times as file formats
- How to mine text

VOLUNTEERING

Dec 2019 - Present Deputy of Student - Parent Association

University of Melbourne, Australia

- Communication Skills
- Ability to work with a variety of managers
- Planning
- Flexibility

Jan 2016 - Jun 2018

Student's Representative

College of Computer Science & Information System, Jazan University, Saudi Arabia

- · Communication skill
- Collaborative work
- Time-Management
- Teach-ability

Jan 2016 - Jun 2018

Volunteer for student services and registration

College of Computer Science & Information System, Jazan University, Saudi Arabia

- Leadership
- Timeliness

Apr 2021 - Present

Programs and projects committee

Charity, Saudi Arabi

• Develop programs and activities and suggest development projects, training and workshop

REFERENCES

- Ronal singh (rr.singh@unimelb.edu.au)
- Abeer Dhafer (aalshehri@student.unimelb.edu.au) Mobile Number (+966 55 363 9353)